[music]
I'm blown away, you know, cuz I've kind
of done the part, you know, the circuit
and this is on another level.
>> Oh, thank you, dude.
>> Everything.
>> Well, got a killer team. Awesome team
>> and uh it wasn't always like this
though, right?
>> Started off in the attic. [laughter]
>> So,
>> that's what he was telling me. Your guy,
man.
>> He said this happened. You were just
sending hard drives, dude. Before that,
it was me and my wife. And I was sitting
here running sound while I was
interviewing. And my wife, we had these
cameras with that would only record 30
minutes at a time. And so my wife would
run back and forth and reset the cameras
depending on who's talking. My girl was,
she goes, "Shawn Ryan," she goes, "How
he uh how he becomes like this? How he
do it? Wait, how he do it?" You know,
like she talks like that. I'm like, "How
he do it? Like, you mean how is he like
a million? How how how do he become
success successful? I said he he he's
got a badass show and he's super
intelligent, smart about it in your
marketing and everything. There's a lot
that goes into it and also you got in.
I'm sure the timing is good, too, but I
don't know.
>> Well, I don't know, man. Probably
>> you got in a while a longer.
>> I just I when I did it, I was like I I
got to I'm going to I'm just going to do
it different than everybody. Everybody
had a purple curtain, you know, the Joe
Rogan curtain.
>> Yeah.
>> And everybody had the headphones and I
was the first one to come on here and I
was like,
>> I'm going to learn how to edit. I'm
going to do previews as promotional
pieces.
>> Nobody was doing that. Nobody had like a
set like this where there was not a mic
shoved in your face and headphones. And
so I just wanted to make it very
relaxed.
>> Yeah.
>> You know what I mean? And so
>> why? And now like everybody's doing it,
which is great. You know, lifted the
whole industry,
>> right? I told myself I was like, you
know, I'm going to tell Sean just I I
know you've been lied to a lot. So my my
number one goal is just not to lie
today. [laughter]
>> You know what I'm saying, brother?
>> Thank you.
>> So try to eliminate some of that,
[laughter]
>> you know, like cuz I saw your interview,
man. I laughed so hard. I can't imagine.
>> Yeah,
I should have expected it.
>> Well, I
My biggest mistake in life I think is my
tr a trusting nature to me. Yeah.
Characteristic is to trust people. Latch
on to people quickly and become friends
and a chameleon kind of like oh yeah
we're best friends now. And I mean it.
It's authentic but but man it's crushed
me.
>> Yeah I know what you mean.
>> You know my you know McAfee what John
McAfee he once told me he said son you
could be a billionaire. He goes but you
got one prom. He said you could be such
a good businessman. I said, "Sir, you
name it and I will I will kill it right
now and I because I want that success.
You name my problem and I'll get rid of
it. I swear to God." He goes, "I'm
sorry, son. You you there's no getting
rid of this one." And I said, "Tell me
and I'll get rid of it." And he says,
"No." And I said, "What then?" He said,
"It's your heart." He said, "That's
what's going to He said, "That's what's
going to get in the way and you won't
become as as successful as you could
be."
And he was right cuz I I have these uh
loyalty things still
>> and I'm better at it now. But once he
said, 'You know your biggest problem,
Jimmy? I said, 'What sir? He could look
right through you and tell you about
your whole life. He said, you lift
people on a pedestal so high, so far
above you that eventually you can't hold
anymore and they just fall on you and
crush you. And I mean, that was pretty
much what I did to my ex-wife. I would
hold people and that's what Miy did to
me. He did that um what's up he would he
would he cared about people. Miy car
care car he he was very untrusting and
and didn't trust anybody even his own
wife because [laughter] because she came
to him if you came to Miy couldn't trust
you. She was a prostitute in Miami.
right when he came back from Bise from
being on the run. He sat down and she
approached him with her friend and he
said, "What are you two women up to
tonight?" And they said, "Well, we've
come to rob old white Richmond." And he
says, "Okay, you can stay because you
told me the truth and your friend could
leave." And so everybody came to him,
even his Green Beret security guards
were able to contact him and stuff. So I
was the only one that he reached out to.
I didn't know him. Yeah. He reached out
to me
and that's where and so the trust. So no
matter what, no matter how paranoid he
got about me, no matter if he called me
a spy, no matter if he saw me take a
letter from somebody outside, even if
it's the lawn bill, he couldn't he had
that's the one thing he that I was
different was that I had never
approached him. And I would remind him
of that. I said, "Sir, I you reached out
to me." So he'd be like, "Fair enough.
Do you still think that little piece of
advice is true that you won't find
extreme success because you're a good
person? Because you have a heart,
because you lift people up, because you
care about people?
>> I'm afraid so.
>> Really? You think that?
>> I I mean,
>> how do you define success?
>> Yeah. How do we define how do I define
success? I think success for me is uh
lighting the torches of other people and
getting my charge from that. If I can
really if I can actually change
somebody's life with my story or the
lighthouse mission of mine, then that
will charge me up, right? But but in
let's get real, success to me right now
is I mean would be making millions of
dollars, you know, the American like the
what everybody wants, right? Um there's
still that in me.
>> Yeah. I don't know. I've made millions
of dollars before and totally crashed
and burned. Mhm. Ruined it. I've had
opportun
opportunities of a life and I've ruined
them. So this time I told God this time
if or when you decide it's time again,
I'm going to do it your way because
Jimmy's way is the road to hell. I think
he could still find all that and be a
good person
>> 100
>> because yeah, you know. Yeah. Well,
maybe he's made billions. I don't know
what the guy was worth to be honest. Was
what was he worth?
>> Maybe maybe people call him a
billionaire, but he probably he sold uh
McAfee for 700 million to uh
>> Yeah, 700 million. So between
all the investments and stuff
afterwards, I'm sure he probably hit the
the billion mark. I don't know. You know
what I mean? I think it's a longer path
like just and I'm nowhere even even in
that realm ballpark.
>> Sean, I seen your setup, Sean. I don't
>> But but I do well, but it it's I I just
think it's a longer road, man. I mean,
when I started this,
I never made it about me. You know what
I mean? It was always about somebody
else. And I saw everybody's business
that I brought on just race right past
mine because of my business, you know
what I mean?
>> Right.
>> And um I mean they were able to take it
and run, you know what I mean? And and
develop something massive, but a lot of
them never would have got the exposure
if it wasn't for this, you know, and and
I used to
>> I used to just think to myself like,
dude, what am I doing wrong here? I'm
paying in time and my money and in in my
heart and soul, you know what I mean, to
lift these other guys up who can't who
would never get this type of exposure
and uh but just but I knew I was doing a
good thing and I knew they deserved it,
you know what I mean? And and I I loved
doing it and I still do. but still get
way more out of that than the financial
aspect. But I just knew I was like, if I
just keep doing it, if you just keep
pumping enough good into the world, it's
going to come back around. And it took
about
what two
two three years and it came back around,
>> bro. It came back around huge. You got
the number one show or number two show
bouncing back and forth.
>> Yeah, we're on top five.
>> That's crazy. But but uh so I don't
know, man. Just keep that in mind. I'm
sure screwing everybody over and not
having a heart and and and no feelings
and all that kind of stuff, I think it's
a much faster track,
>> but I think it leads to a empty soul,
which isn't success anyways,
>> right? It's a fast track. Um but one
thing it taught me, Sean, was
forgiveness. Um, I had to walk through a
tremendous amount of forgiveness of my
ex uh you for taking a ton of Bitcoin
and and money and all kinds of stuff.
And you know, think about it every time
Bitcoin goes up, right? When it's at a
huge dip right now, but when it goes up,
I had like I had like a 100 Bitcoin at
one time. Like I have
>> You had 100 Bitcoin,
>> brother. I had brother I I'm not joking
when I talk about money. I you know, and
and I had so much. And so every time
Bitcoin goes up, can you imagine? I have
[clears throat] zero now. Can you
imagine like the feelings of that? But
so that's where I walk out that
forgiveness piece. But God taught me
some lessons. Maki taught me lessons and
that I I take into my life now that's
created success. I consider success. Um
and those and there's been a lot of life
lessons, you know.
>> I'll bet.
>> You know, I'll bet
>> you got a book. You're writing a book.
>> Yeah. It's it's been a it's been like a
look what happened. So, I got my story
out there and um one of these big
publishing companies picked it up. Uh a
major one, two works, something and
something. Um I won't put up their name
out, but they offered a big advance for
my story and I needed it, Sean. I don't
have the Bitcoin anymore. I don't have
the money, so I needed I got my little
baby. This is just a couple years ago.
Uh and I said, "Okay, okay." And my
agent was like, "It's going to happen."
But they it was about to be sent. But
they said they just need one little
change to your story. They need to tweak
it a little bit. I said, "Okay, let me
know. I'll put the delete hit the delete
button." And they said, "Well, it's kind
[clears throat] of the part about Jesus,
how he met you." And I said, "Oh, no
deal." I said, "No deal." I said, "I
guess I'll have to write this sucker on
my own."
>> Why? Why isn't they always want that
out?
>> They want it out because it's the truth.
They want the truth out
>> to keep us guessing and keep us
distorted and disillusioned. It'll
probably be that much bigger. I mean,
>> well, that's why it's only $9 because I
wrote it against [laughter]
Hold fast, man. But
>> well, I mean, they did it to Mel Gibson.
>> Yeah. With the passion, you know, they
Nobody would fund him.
>> Nobody would fund the guy, you know.
Everybody, they went after him. All
those attacks, everything. They'll never
watch it. Like just discouraged him and
tried to destroy him. And then the movie
wound up breaking the record. It was
like what 600 $600 million movie or
something. The Passion.
>> Yeah.
>> And it hasn't been broken until
>> I think it's just been the last couple
years. It It was It was undefeated with
inflation
for like 20 I think it's like 20
something years.
>> My goodness.
>> You know what I mean?
>> Dang.
>> And they all self-funded.
>> I just self-published.
>> Yeah, I'm doing self-published. and know
I don't know what I'm doing mo most of
the time but but um I h I I know how to
tell a story at least and I can put it
on paper and my wife has been really
encouraging to do it. She said, "Jimmy,
you got to get this story. You got to
get your story out to people." And but I
didn't. But I always said, "Jean, if if
you're gonna if if you're if a book is